原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
第六季 第八集
权力的游戏
我的儿子
My son.
我的长子
My firstborn son.
我的小国王  别出声
My child king, hush.
你听  诸神在为你歌唱
Listen to the gods, for you they sing.
不必再战斗了  好孩子
Fight no more, sweet child.
你的战争大获全胜
Your wars are won.
恶狼通通埋葬
The wolves are buried
伪鹿尽数伏诛
and the false stag done.
合上你的蓝眼睛  我的宝贝
Shut your blue eyes, my love.
让王冠坠落吧
Let the crown fall.
天父向你招手  邀你去他的厅堂
The Father above beckons you to his hall.
七层天堂里我们再团聚
In Seventh Heaven I'll see you once more.
但现在我要复仇  向珊莎这个娼妇
But now I seek vengeance on Sansa the whore
还有我弟弟小恶魔
and my brother the Imp
他们谋害了自己的君王
who killed his own king.
他生于狮群之中  是我们家族的诅咒
Born amongst lions, our curse from within.
我要杀死他  我发誓
I will slay him, I swear.
用绞索  或者刀子
With noose or with knife,
无论要花两周  一个月
though it take me a fortnight,
还是穷尽一生
a moon or my life.
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Silmar 草草  盐湖凉开水
■
翻译：妖精希亚 山猫 泰斯
校对：泰斯·雪诺 Silmar   顾问：屈畅(ccxx)
时间轴：崽猪 aaaBao 加森 Avis
我听到闻到的是什么
What is that I hear and smell?
马上就会被我送入地狱的人
Someone I'll soon send to hell.
后期：吉吉·波顿  总监：泰斯·雪诺
是时候见证传言的真假了
It's time to see if truth they told
据说泰温·兰尼斯特能拉出黄金
who said Tywin Lannister shits gold.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
拿假发来
Get the wig!
你这个禽兽  禽兽  你害死了我的妻子
You beast, you beast. You killed my wife.
现在又杀了亲生父亲
And now you've taken your father's life.
没有比你更大逆不道的儿子了
No worse child ever stained this land.
我诅咒为你命名的那一天
I curse the day I named you.
这是我最大的罪孽
My greatest crime!
包得真好
You're good at that.
在哪儿学的
Where did you learn?
我是个善妒的女人
I'm a jealous woman.
总是喜欢上坏男人
I've always liked bad men
他们也总是喜欢我
and they've always liked me.
他们会夜里回到那不像个家的家
They'd come home wherever home was that night
身上满是妓女的香水味
stinking of some whore's perfume.
然后我们大打出手  我捅他们个窟窿
So we'd fight and I'd put a hole in them.
事后我又难过起来
And then I'd feel terrible,
就给他们包扎
so I'd patch them up.
包扎手法就练起来了
I got good at patching them up.
捅人手法也练起来了
And good at putting holes in them.
是啊
And that.
那个女演员怎样了
What happened to the actress?
那个想要你死的
The one who wanted you dead.
比安卡
Bianca.
她以后想出去当演员可要难了
She'll have a hard time finding work as an actress
脸被我弄成那样
after what I did to her face.
我一直没学会做饭
I never did learn to cook.
但是吃吧  吃下去  你需要吃东西
But eat. Eat. You need it.
戏班子很快要去潘托斯了
The company is moving on to Pentos soon.
你该跟我们走
You should come with us.
-我不能  -为什么不能
- I can't. - Why not?
我有直觉  你会擅长这一行的
Got a feeling you'd be good at this sort of work.
再说了  我们还缺一个女演员
And besides, we need a new actress.
我想我记不住那么多台词
I don't think I could remember all of the lines.
跟我们走吧
Come with us.
你在这里还有什么牵挂的
What's left for you here?
那你们就不安全了
You wouldn't be safe.
只要她还在找我
Not while she's looking for me.
谁
Who?
她没有名字
She doesn't have a name.
你要去哪里
Where will you go?
厄索斯在东  维斯特洛在西
Essos is east and Westeros is west.
但维斯特洛西边是什么呢
But what's west of Westeros?
我不知道
I don't know.
没人知道
Nobody does.
所有地图到那儿就结束了
That's where all the maps stop.
可能是世界的边缘吧
The edge of the world, maybe.
我想去看看
I'd like to see that.
-那是什么  -罂粟花奶
- What's that? - Milk of the poppy.
我不想喝
I don't want any.
睡一觉你才能恢复
Sleep is the only way you'll heal.
相信我  喝我的汤都没死  喝什么都不会死
Trust me, if my soup didn't kill you, nothing will.
说起加廷斯  他从前可俊俏了
Thing about Gatins, right, is he used to be pretty.
我那时候是接吻高手
I was a famous kisser.
你们这群小子知道怎么接吻吗
You lads know how to kiss proper?
我们当然知道
Course we do.
高手才会  是技术
This is for masters, this technique.
-你还没准备好  -我准备好了
- You're not ready. - I'm ready.
他说他准备好了
He says he's ready.
好吧  瞧仔细了
All right. Now, pay attention.
左手托在她脑后
You put your left hand on the back of the lady's head.
右手像这样搂住她的小腰
Your right hand holds the small of the lady's back like so.
非常浪漫
Very romantic.
伸出中指
Take your middle finger, yeah,
直戳进她的小洞里
and you jam it right up her bunghole.
就差那么一点
So fucking close!
闻着跟小屄一个味儿
Ah, it smells like pussy to me.
瞧瞧他  硬了没有  小子
Look at him. You get hard, boy?
操你妈  恶心的老变态
Fuck you! Disgusting old twats.
还乐呢  是不是  老王八
Got off on that, did you, you old fuck?
另一个呢
Where's the other one?
-黄斗篷那个  -操
- The one with the yellow cloak. - Fuck you!
这就是你的遗言  操
Those are your last words, fuck you?
再想想  想个好词儿
Come on, you can do better.
骚屄
Cunt!
你要屎尿横流地死了  知道吗
You're shit at dying, you know that?
她自火中重生  给世界带来新生
丹妮莉丝是光之王给她的孩子的恩赐
若我们对女王和她的忠实仆从的爱坚定不移
就没有人能再给我们戴上枷锁
真是成功的开始
I'd call that a successful gambit.
-是吗  -看看你周围
- Would you? - Look around.
城市恢复了活力
The city has come back to life.
通过跟狂热分子达成协议
You made a pact with fanatics.
没错  而且成功了
I did and it worked.
如果你用剃刀剃须
If you shaved your beard with a straight razor,
也可以说剃刀有用
you'd say the razor worked.
但那不说明它割不了你喉咙
That doesn't mean it won't cut your throat.
一听就是从没刮过胡子的人
Spoken like a man who has never had to shave.
我会想你的
I'm going to miss you.
我知道
I know.
希望你远征的主意没打错
I hope you're right about this expedition of yours.
如果我没回来  你就知道我错了
If I don't return, you'll know I was wrong.
我们需要在维斯特洛有朋友
We need friends in Westeros.
也需要船只
And we need ships.
最重要的是  我们需要我们的女王
Most of all, we need our queen.
她会回来的  她必须回来
She'll come back. She has to.
我的心已经碎过太多次了
My heart's been broken too many times already.
剩下的路我自己走吧
I'll walk the rest of the way myself.
我要是想去执行秘密任务
I can't go off on a secret mission
就不能有全城最出名的侏儒陪着
in the company of the most famous dwarf in the city.
瓦里斯
Varys.
是全世界最出名的侏儒
The most famous dwarf in the world.
陛下  几名战士之子
Your Grace, several members of the Faith Militant
被准许进入了红堡
have been permitted entry to the Red Keep.
被准许
Have been permitted?
这么说真委婉
That's rather a tortured way of putting it.
他们要求见您  陛下
They demand to see you, Your Grace.
谁批准他们进红堡的
Who permitted them inside the Red Keep?
国王知道他们来吗
The king is aware of their presence?
是的  陛下
He is, Your Grace.
他现在在房间里祈祷
He's currently in his chambers at prayer.
陛下  总主教大人
Your Grace, His Holiness the High Septon
要在贝勒大圣堂跟您谈谈
wishes to speak with you at the Great Sept of Baelor.
总主教大人
His Holiness the High Septon
可以来红堡见我
is welcome to see me here in the Red Keep.
陛下  这并非请求
Your Grace, this is not a request.
这是请求  蓝赛尔堂弟
It is a request, Cousin Lancel.
你要我做件事  我拒绝了
You are asking me for something, I'm refusing.
总主教要见您
The High Septon commands you.
您真要拒绝他吗
Are you sure you want to refuse him?
他保证过  审判之前我可以留在红堡
He promised me I could stay in the Red Keep until my trial.
他没有许过这种承诺
He made no such promises.
-如果您不肯自愿前往  -滚出去
- If you refuse to come of your own free will-- - Get out.
让开  爵士
Move aside, ser.
命令您的人让开  否则我们动手了
Order your man to step aside or there will be violence.
那就动手吧
I choose violence.
请转告总主教  他随时可以来
Please tell His High Holiness he's always welcome to visit.
像是在围城  小姐
Looks like a siege, my lady.
你真有军事头脑  波德
You have a keen military mind, Pod.
小姐  小姐
My lady. My lady.
来者何人
Who goes there?!
所为何事
State your business!
我是塔斯的布蕾妮
My name is Brienne of Tarth.
请转告詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士  我有话跟他说
Please inform Ser Jaime Lannister I've come to speak with him.
告诉他我有他的剑
Tell him I have his sword.
瞧咱们俩  老大了还做侍从
Getting a bit old to be a squire, aren't we?
他娘的波德瑞克·派恩
Podrick fucking Payne.
我以为你早没命了
I thought you'd be dead by now.
还有气呢
Not yet.
他们在里面
Are they in there?
你说他们在里面干上了吗
You think they're fucking?
什么
What?
当然没有
No.
为什么  换我就干她
Why not? I'd fuck her.
你也会吧
You'd fuck her, wouldn't you?
我是她的侍从
I'm her squire.
好吧  他肯定会干她
Well, he'd fuck her, that's for sure.
她也愿意干  不是吗
And she'd fuck him, don't you think?
瞧她看他那眼神
The way she looks at him.
所有女人都那么看他  真让人受不了
The way all women look at him is frankly irritating.
在这方面  我更喜欢跟随他弟弟
I preferred working with the little brother on that account.
得了  你那根神棍厉害着呢
Come on, you're the one with the magic cock.
你肯定给她展示过吧
You must have shown it to her by now.
-她在训练我打斗  -是吗
- She's training me to fight. - Is she?
早上一小时  晚上一小时
An hour in the morning, an hour at night.
每天如此
Every day.
那我这样的老头子
Then how come an old cunt like me
怎么还是能摸上来杀了你
can still sneak up and murder you?
不是那种打斗
Well, that's a different sort of fighting.
这话不假
Now, that's the truth, isn't it?
你想学这种打斗吗
You want to learn that sort of fighting?
好吧
All right.
先从步法讲起
All right, let's start with your footwork.
给我看看你的站姿
Show me your stance.
听好  波德
Now listen to me, Pod.
你两脚相隔一码  看到了吗
See how your feet are about a yard apart?
第一课  假定所有人都想揍你
Lesson number one, assume everyone wants to hit you.
因为事实如此  波德  所有人都想揍侍从
'Cause they do, Pod. Everyone wants to hit a fucking squire.
再来一次  来嘛  别生闷气
Do it again. Come on, don't sulk.
没想到你真能找到她
I never thought you'd find her.
我以为珊莎已经死了
I just assumed Sansa was dead.
你为什么要那么想
Why would you assume that?
依我的经验  她那样的姑娘活不长
In my experience, girls like her don't live very long.
你应该不认识几个她那样的姑娘吧
I don't think you know many girls like her.
我为你骄傲
Well, I'm proud of you.
真的  你克服万难兑现了
I am. You fulfilled your oath
你对凯特琳·史塔克的誓言
to Catelyn Stark against all odds.
当然了  我姐姐想要珊莎死
Of course, my sister wants Sansa dead.
那姑娘仍是杀害乔佛里的嫌疑人
The girl is still a suspect in Joffrey's murder,
这是个麻烦
so there is that complication.
你来做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
我来找黑鱼
I've come for the Blackfish.
他归你了
You're welcome to have him.
珊莎小姐要从波顿家手中夺回她世袭的位置
Lady Sansa desires to take her ancestral seat back from the Boltons
名正言顺地成为临冬城城主
and assume her rightful position as Lady of Winterfell.
她打算凭什么军队夺下临冬城
With what army does she plan on taking Winterfell?
徒利家的军队
The Tully army.
他们现在有点忙
They're a bit occupied at the moment.
我是被派来夺回奔流城的
I was sent here to reclaim Riverrun
而目前徒利叛军在守城
currently defended by the Tully rebels,
你能明白我的难处吧
so you can see the conundrum.
徒利家的人保卫家园就成叛军了
The Tullys are rebels because they're fighting for their home?
奔流城按圣旨已被赐予佛雷家
Riverrun was granted to the Freys by royal decree.
作为背叛罗柏·史塔克  屠杀他一家的奖赏
As a reward for betraying Robb Stark and slaughtering his family.
没错
Exactly.
我们不该争政治上的事
We shouldn't argue about politics.
你是个骑士  詹姆爵士
You're a knight, Ser Jaime.
我知道你有荣誉感
I know there is honor in you.
-我亲眼见过  -我是兰尼斯特
- I've seen it myself. - I'm a Lannister.
别让我背叛自己的家族
Don't ask me to betray my own house.
我不会做那种事
I do no such thing.
兵不血刃地占领奔流城
Take Riverrun without bloodshed.
完成任务后  带你的军队原路返回吧
Ride south again with your mission complete and your army intact.
你有什么提议
What do you propose?
让我进奔流城劝降
Allow me to enter Riverrun under a flag of truce.
让我劝说黑鱼放弃守城
Let me try to persuade the Blackfish to give up the castle.
他有何理由弃守祖居地
Why would he abandon his ancestral home?
因为你允许他率领徒利家的军队北上
Because you'll allow him to lead the Tully forces safely north.
你见过黑鱼吗
Have you ever met the Blackfish?
-没见过  -他比你还顽固
- No. - He's even more stubborn than you are.
好吧
All right.
试试跟那头老山羊讲道理吧
Try to talk some sense into the old goat.
他可能听不进去  但他的手下可能会
He won't listen, but his men might.
不是所有人都愿意舍命保卫别人的家园
Not everybody wants to die for someone else's home.
我需要你的保证
I need your word.
如果我说服他弃守城堡
If I persuade him to abandon the castle,
你就放他们平安北上
you'll grant a safe passage north.
我向你保证
You have my word.
以天黑为限
You have until nightfall.
你把它给我是为了一项使命
You gave it to me for a purpose.
那项使命我已达成
I've achieved that purpose.
它是你的
It's yours.
它永远属于你
It will always be yours.
最后一件事  詹姆爵士
One last thing, Ser Jaime.
什么事  布蕾妮小姐
Yes, Lady Brienne?
我若没能说服黑鱼投降
Should I fail to persuade the Blackfish to surrender
等你攻打城堡的时候
and if you attack the castle,
荣誉将驱使我为珊莎的家族而战
honor compels me to fight for Sansa's kin.
当然
Of course it does.
也就是与你为敌
To fight you.
希望事情不要发展到那种地步
Let's hope it doesn't come to that.
我已经拒绝你三次了
I've said no three times already.
我有你外侄孙女珊莎·史塔克的亲笔信
I have a signed letter from your niece Sansa Stark.
她长大后我就没见过她
I haven't seen her since she was a child.
我不熟悉她的字迹  也不认识你
I don't know her signature. I don't know you.
而且我不会投降  今晚守备力量加倍
And I will not surrender. Double the guards tonight.
弑君者想试探我们
The Kingslayer wants to try us.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
我再说一次  我的名字是...
As I have said, my name is--
塔斯的布蕾妮  我认识你的父亲
Yes, Brienne of Tarth. I know your father.
-是条好汉  -他非常欣赏您
- Good man. - He always spoke highly of you.
即使现在他就在这里  我也会对他说同样的话
And if he were here now, I'd tell him the same I'm telling you.
如果你认为我会因为弑君者的保证
If you think I'm abandoning my family's seat
就放弃家族的根基所在  那你就是个白痴
on the Kingslayer's word of honor, you're a bloody fool.
奔流城顶不住兰尼斯特家与佛雷家的进攻
Riverrun cannot stand against the Lannisters and the Freys.
我们坚持的时间会超过你那个独手朋友的想象
We can stand longer than your one-handed friend thinks we can.
-他不是我的朋友  -不是吗
- He's not my friend. - No?
那是谁允许你
Who gave you permission
穿过围城大军进到城堡里来的
to cross the siege line and enter the castle?
是谁给了你那把柄头雕着金狮子的剑
Who gave you that sword with the gold lion on the pommel?
詹姆爵士对你的侄女凯特琳·史塔克信守了诺言
Ser Jaime kept his word to your niece Catelyn Stark.
他请我完成凯特琳的遗愿  寻找并帮助珊莎
He sent me to find Sansa, to help her as Catelyn wanted.
他送我这把剑是让我保护她
He gave me this sword to protect her.
我保护过她  也将一如既往
That is what I have done and I will continue to do
至死不渝
until the day I die.
她真像她的母亲
She's exactly like her mother.
我的人手不够她攻打临冬城
I don't have enough men to help her take Winterfell.
你的人手比她多
You have more than she does.
她想夺回家园  这我理解
She wants her home back. I understand that.
但这里是我的家园
But this is my home.
如果詹姆·兰尼斯特想占领它
And if Jaime Lannister wants it,
他得跟别人一样老老实实攻城
he can bloody well take it the way everyone else does.
去找学士
Find the maester.
我们需要一只信鸦给珊莎送信
We need to get a raven north to Sansa.
信上写什么
What should I write?
就说我失败了
Tell her I failed.
是有圣旨要宣布吗
There's to be a royal announcement?
是的
There is.
为什么我没得到通知
Why wasn't I informed?
此时此刻
There is to be a royal announcement
将有圣旨
in the throne room
在王座厅宣布
at this very moment.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
站在我儿子身边
To stand by my son.
你的位置在廊厅里
Your place is in the gallery
和宫里的夫人小姐一起
with the other ladies of the court.
陛下
Your Grace...
诸位大人  夫人
Lords and ladies,
信仰和王权
the Faith and the Crown
是世界赖以依存的两大支柱
are the two pillars that hold up this world.
一根倾颓  另一根也不保
One collapses, so does the other.
天父审判所有人
The Father judges us all.
只要触犯了神的律法
If you break his laws...
就要受到惩罚
you will be punished.
在与总主教大人商议之后
After conferring with His Holiness the High Septon,
我们决定  对洛拉斯·提利尔
we have determined that Loras Tyrell
与瑟曦·兰尼斯特的审判
and Cersei Lannister's trial
将于圣母节的第一天
will be held in the Great Sept of Baelor
在贝勒大圣堂举行
on the first day of the Festival of the Mother.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
另外  经过再三祷告与反思
Furthermore, after much prayer and reflection,
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
国王决定从今日起
the Crown has decided that from this day forward,
在七国之内废除比武审判
trial by combat will be forbidden throughout the Seven Kingdoms.
这是一个野蛮的传统
The tradition is a brutish one,
是腐朽的统治者们阴谋设计的把戏
a scheme devised by corrupt rulers
以逃避诸神的公正审判
in order to avoid true judgment from the gods.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特和洛拉斯·提利尔
Cersei Lannister and Loras Tyrell
将按照教会早期的做法
will stand trial before seven septons
在七名修士面前接受审判
as it was in the earliest days of the Faith.
七神保佑你们
Seven blessings to all.
七神保佑
Seven blessings.
陛下
Your Grace...
您说的那个古老的传闻
that old rumor you told me about.
我的小小鸟儿调查过了
My little birds investigated.
结果呢
And?
那只是个传闻吗  还是超出我们的所知
Was it just a rumor or something more?
超出
More.
远远超出
Much more.
你好像很开心
You seem happy.
我就是很开心
I am happy.
你们俩也应该开心
You should both be happy as well.
不久之前  这座城市差点自掘坟墓
Not so long ago, this city was ready to devour itself.
现在它就像起死回生了
Now it's like a man reborn.
女王回来我才会开心
I will be happy when our queen returns.
你怎么不喝酒  你俩怎么都不喝酒
Why don't you drink? Why don't either of you ever drink?
无垢者不饮酒
Unsullied never drink.
-为什么  -规矩
- Why not? - Rules.
谁定的规矩
And who made these rules?
你们以前的主人吗
Your former masters?
那些无耻之徒在扼杀你们的人性
Those miserable old shits didn't want you to be human.
跟我喝一杯
Have a drink with me.
你呢  你有什么借口
And you? What's your excuse?
我以前尝过酒
I have tried wine before.
感觉不舒服
It made me feel funny.
那就是酒劲上来了
That's how you know it's working.
敬我们的女王
Here's to our queen.
不喝就是对女王不敬
Anyone not drinking is disrespecting our queen.
敬风暴降生丹妮莉丝  龙之母
To Daenerys Stormborn, Mother of Dragons,
解放者  愿她统治长久
Breaker of Chains, long may she reign.
-愿她统治长久  -愿她统治长久
- Long may she reign. - Long may she reign.
好喝吗
Do you like it?
像是变了味的
Tastes like it has turned.
是的  发酵
Yes, yes. Fermentation.
总有一天  等我们的女王夺取了七国
One day, after our queen has taken the Seven Kingdoms...
我要有自己的葡萄园
I'd like to have my own vineyard.
酿自己的酒
Make my own wine.
"小恶魔喜酿"
The Imp's Delight.
只有我的好朋友才能喝
Only my close friends could drink it.
给我讲个笑话  纳斯岛的弥桑黛
Tell me a joke, Missandei of Naath.
我没什么笑话讲
I do not know any jokes.
灰虫子
Grey Worm?
好吧
Right.
三位贵族走进一家酒馆
Three lords walk into a tavern--
一个史塔克  一个马泰尔  一个兰尼斯特
a Stark, a Martell, and a Lannister.
他们要了麦芽酒
They order ale,
可当酒保上酒后
but when the barkeep brings them over,
他们都发现自己杯里有只苍蝇
each of them finds a fly in his cup.
兰尼斯特拍案而起
The Lannister, outraged,
摔了杯子  又点了一杯
shoves the cup aside and demands another.
马泰尔把苍蝇择出来  然后一口吞掉
The Martell plucks the fly out and swallows it whole.
史塔克把手伸进杯子
The Stark reaches into his cup,
揪出苍蝇  大喊道
pulls out the fly and shouts,
"吐出来  小东西  给我吐出来"
"Spit it out, you wee shit. Spit it out."
在维斯特洛讲才好笑
It's funnier in Westeros.
史塔克和兰尼斯特  我认为都是敌人
The Starks and the Lannisters, I thought these were enemies.
是的
Yes.
笑话跟故事一样  灰虫子
A joke is like a story, Torgo Nudho.
不一定是真实的故事
Not a true story, necessarily.
是为了逗你发笑的故事
A story that's supposed to make you laugh ideally.
也许不合时宜
Not at the moment, perhaps.
弥桑黛  喜欢这酒吗
Missandei, do you like the wine?
喜欢
I do.
讲个笑话吧
Tell a joke.
一条快沉的船上有两个翻译
Two translators are on a sinking ship.
第一个说
The first says,
"你会游泳吗"
"Do you know how to swim?"
第二个说  "不会  但我会用十九种语言喊救命"
The second says, "No, but I can shout for help in 19 languages."
这是我听过的最烂的笑话
That is the worst joke I ever heard.
你都不知道什么是笑话
You don't even know what a joke is.
我当了一辈子兵  你觉得我没听过笑话吗
I am soldier all my life. You think I never hear joke?
你耍我们啊
You lied to us.
我开玩笑的
I make joke.
再来一个
More jokes.
有一次我带着蜂窝和驴子进了妓院
I once walked into a brothel with a honeycomb and a jackass.
鸨母说...
The madam says--
[瓦雷利亚语]
奴隶主要来夺回自己的财产了
The Masters have come for their property.
艾德慕大人
Lord Edmure.
我为佛雷家让你受的委屈向你道歉
I apologize for the way the Freys treated you.
你这样的身份应该被善待
A man of your birth deserves better.
我向你保证  从现在起你将衣食无忧
You have my word you'll be properly fed and clothed from now on.
你向我保证
I have your word?
好啊
Oh, good.
很好  真是...
Good, that's--
真是件好事
that's a fine thing.
我叔叔不会放弃城堡的  爵士
My uncle will never surrender the castle, ser.
不管你玩什么把戏
Whatever game you're playing.
黑鱼已经老了
The Blackfish is an old man.
善终是他唯一的指望
A good death is all he can hope for.
至于你  你现在有个孩子了  我听说
But you, you have a child now, I've heard.
你婚礼当晚播下的种子
A son you sired on your wedding night.
你是条好汉
You're a potent man.
一个过了洞房夜
A son I've never met
就没见过的妻子生下的
born of a wife that I haven't seen
未曾谋面的儿子
since our first night together.
你应该跟他们在一起
You should be with them both.
我可以安排  你知道吗
I can arrange that, you realize?
凯岩城里有舒服的房间
Comfortable rooms for you at Casterly Rock.
有教师培养你的儿子
A tutor for your boy,
有骑士训练他战斗和骑马
knights to train him to fight and to ride.
等他到了年龄  他将拥有自己的城堡
And when he comes of age, he'll have a keep of his own.
你当自己是正派人吗
Do you imagine yourself a decent person?
是不是
Is that it?
别忘了你曾屠杀我的家人
After you've massacred my family.
把我关在牢里好几年
Kept me in a cell for years.
抢占我们的土地
Stolen our lands.
我得提醒你  我们两家正在交战
I'll remind you that our houses are at war.
很抱歉这场冲突打扰了你
I'm sorry if this conflict has inconvenienced you,
但是反抗国王的后果是很严重的
but rebelling against the Crown does have consequences.
说这话的人从背后捅了他的国王
Says the man who shoved his sword through his king's back.
我让你误以为这是在谈判吗
Did I give you the impression that this was a negotiation?
不是的
It's not.
你明白  某种程度上你明白
You understand. On some level you understand
你是个恶人
that you're an evil man.
让诸神来判断吧
I'll leave the judgments to the gods.
那倒是方便
Well, that is convenient for you.
你长得蛮英俊  不是吗
You're a fine-looking fellow, aren't you?
方下巴
Your square jaw,
黄金战甲
your golden armor.
告诉我  我想知道
Tell me, I want to know.
真想知道
I truly do.
你是怎么说服自己的
How do you live with yourself?
我们都需要相信
All of us have to believe
自己是正派人  不是吗
that we're decent, don't we?
你晚上也得睡觉
You have to sleep at night.
你干了那么多坏事
How do you tell yourself
到底是怎么
that you're decent
让自己问心无愧的
after everything that you've done?
我以前被你姐姐俘虏
I was your sister's prisoner once.
没记错的话  她拿块石头砸我的脑袋
She hit me on the head with a rock if I remember correctly.
是啊
Yeah.
她应该杀了你
She should have killed you.
也许吧  但她没杀我
Perhaps, but she didn't.
凯特琳·史塔克恨我  和你一样
Catelyn Stark hated me just like you hate me.
但我不恨她
But I didn't hate her.
我很佩服她
I admired her.
比她的丈夫和儿子还让我佩服
Far more than her husband or her son.
你觉得我管你佩服谁不佩服谁吗
Do you think I care whom you admire and whom you don't?
不  但我就是要讲  因为你是俘虏
No, I don't, but I'm telling you anyway because you're my prisoner.
你没得选
You don't have a choice.
她对她孩子的爱
The love she had for her children,
让我肃然起敬
I was a little awed by it.
让我想起我姐姐
Reminded me of my sister.
哦  我明白了
Oh. Oh, I see.
你是个疯子
You're a madman.
我不是来和你互相羞辱的
I'm not here to trade insults.
-你姐姐很坚强...  -别说凯特了
- Your sister was a strong-- - Don't talk about Cat!
我想说谁就说谁
I'll talk about whomever I want.
她爱她孩子
She loved her children.
天下母亲都爱孩子
I suppose all mothers do,
但像凯特琳和瑟曦那样
but Catelyn and Cersei,
爱得那么强烈的很少见
there's a fierceness you don't often see.
她们为了保护孩子可以不择手段
They'd do anything to protect their babies.
挑起战争
Start a war.
烧掉城市  放走最危险的敌人
Burn cities to ash. Free their worst enemies.
我们为爱所做的事
The things we do for love.
你来不是为了谈论我们的姐姐
You didn't come here to talk about our sisters.
我就是来谈这个的
That's exactly why I came here.
我爱瑟曦
I love Cersei.
你想笑就笑吧
You can laugh at that if you want.
尽管嘲笑我  没关系
You can sneer. Doesn't matter.
她需要我
She needs me.
为了回到她身边  我必须攻下奔流城
And to get back to her, I have to take Riverrun.
我会找你的宝贝儿子过来
I'll send for your baby boy.
我会把他用投石机扔进奔流城里
And I'll launch him into Riverrun with a catapult.
因为你对我不重要  艾德慕大人
Because you don't matter to me, Lord Edmure.
你儿子对我不重要
Your son doesn't matter to me.
城堡里的人对我不重要
The people in the castle don't matter to me.
重要的只有瑟曦
Only Cersei.
如果为了回到她身边
And if I have to slaughter every Tully
我必须杀光徒利家的人
who ever lived to get back to her,
我会的
that's what I'll do.
什么人
Who goes there?
艾德慕·徒利
Edmure Tully,
霍斯特·徒利之子
son of Hoster Tully
合法的奔流城公爵
and the rightful Lord of Riverrun.
我要进城
I demand entry.
别放他进来
Don't let him in.
他是奔流城公爵
He's the Lord of Riverrun.
我必须服从他的命令
I have to obey his commands.
自从红色婚礼上国王被杀
He's been their captive
他就一直是敌人的俘虏
ever since they murdered his king at the Red Wedding.
你觉得在红色婚礼上杀害国王的人
Why do you think the people who murdered his king at the Red Wedding
凭什么决定放他回家
would decide to let him come home?
因为这是圈套  你这个白痴
Because it's a trap, you idiot.
别放他进来
Don't let him in.
他是我的城主  大人
He's my lord, my lord.
我发誓效忠奔流城公爵  服从他的命令
I've sworn to serve the Lord of Riverrun and obey his commands.
你服从的不是艾德慕的命令
You're not obeying Edmure's commands.
你服从的是该死的弑君者的命令
You're obeying the fucking Kingslayer's commands.
我要进城
I demand entry.
城主下令了
My lord has given an order.
他是受人胁迫
With a knife to his throat.
这种命令是无效的
That is not a valid order.
放下吊桥  为艾德慕大人打开城门
Lower the drawbridge and open the gate for Lord Ed...
是  爵士
Aye, ser.
交出奔流城之前我要先砍了你的头
I'll have your head before I surrender Riverrun.
你不是这儿的城主  大人
You are not lord of this castle, my lord.
-放下吊桥  -是  爵士
- Lower the drawbridge. - Aye, ser!
如果你错了
If you're wrong,
我们就放走了最有价值的战俘
we've just surrendered our most valuable prisoner.
欢迎回家  大人
Welcome home, my lord.
命令城堡全体守卫放下武器
Command all the forces within the castle to lay down their arms.
打开城门
Open the gates.
-大人  -你的城主已经下了命令
- My lord... - Your lord has given a command.
步兵  前进
Infantry, advance!
找到黑鱼
Find the Blackfish.
把他捆起来交给佛雷
Put him in irons and hand him over to the Freys.
去找他
Find him.
快走
Go on.
跟我们走吧
Come with us.
我在红色婚礼上已经逃过一次
I've run before from the Red Wedding.
我不能再逃了  这是我的家
I'm not running again. This is my family home.
你的家在北境  跟我们走吧
Your family is in the North. Come with us.
你还能为亲人而战  别白洒一腔热血
Don't die for pride when you can fight for your blood.
你侍奉珊莎比我更称职
You'll serve Sansa far better than I ever could.
快下去
All the way down!
-搜底下  -快走吧
- Check that out! - Go on, now.
我很多年没有真刀真枪地打了
I haven't had a proper sword fight in years.
十之八九要出丑了
I expect I'll make a damn fool of myself.
我们找到黑鱼了  大人
We found the Blackfish, my lord.
好
Good.
把他带来
Bring him to me.
他战死了  大人
He died fighting, my lord.
-我错了  我承认  -那也没用
- I was wrong. I admit it. - That changes nothing.
无垢者可以在滩头建立防线
The Unsullied could mount a defense off the beachhead.
-如果奴隶大军...  -你别再说话了
- If the slavers' forces-- - No more talking from you.
正是你说的话害了我们
Your talking gave us this.
我已经承认了  我是在...
And I have acknowledged that. I'm trying--
你是在告诉我军队该怎么做
You're trying to tell me what the army should do.
你不知道军队该怎么做
You do not know what the army should do.
好吧  军队该怎么做
All right, what should the army do?
我们不去海边
We'll not go to the beach.
如果我们去了海边  奴隶主就会占领金字塔
If we go to the beach, the Masters will take the pyramid.
金字塔是城内我们唯一能守住的地方
The pyramid is the only place in the city we can defend.
-我们留在这里  -然后呢
- We stay here. - And then?
我们等着他们冲进来
We wait for them to come to us.
然后拼死抵抗
Then we fight them.
克里冈
Clegane.
你他妈的来干什么
What the fuck you doing here?
追杀他们  你们呢
Chasing them. You?
吊死他们
Hanging them.
有什么理由吗
Any particular reason?
他们是我们的人  以前是
They're our men. Or they were.
他们袭击了附近的一座修道院  杀了村民
They attacked a nearby sept and murdered the villagers.
你为什么追杀他们
Why do you want them?
一样的理由
Same reason.
我在那儿帮着建房子
I was helping build it.
他们杀了我的一个朋友
They killed a friend of mine.
你还有朋友
You've got friends?
现在没了  他们归我
Not anymore. They're mine.
他们玷污了兄弟会的好名声
It's the Brotherhood's good name they've dragged through the dirt.
去你的名声  他们归我
Fuck your name. They're mine.
我杀过你一次  唐德利恩
I killed you once before, Dondarrion.
很乐意再杀一次
Happy to do it again.
放下弓箭  臭娘们
Drop that arrow, you bloody girl.
好些比你野的娘们也打过杀我的主意
Tougher girls than you have tried to kill me.
你可以处决一个
You can have one of them.
两个
Two.
不行不行
No, no, no.
我们不是屠夫  吊死他们
We're not butchers. We hang them.
吊死
Hanging?
一瞬间就完事了
All over in an instant.
那算个屁的惩罚
Where's the punishment in that?
-他们会死  -我们都会死
- They die. - We all bloody die.
除了那个家伙
Except this one here.
我只砍一个
I'll only gut one of them.
不行
No.
我砍一只手总行吧
I'll chop off one hand.
因为你受的损失  我们给了你三人当中的两个
We gave you two of the three out of respect for your loss.
很对得起你了
That's generous.
一群娘们
Bunch of nancies.
要是以前  为了砍死这三个
There was a time I would have killed all seven of you
我会把你们七个全杀了
just to gut these three.
你老了  克里冈
You're getting old, Clegane.
还没呢
He's not.
饶命  我什么都给你
Please don't. I'll give you anything.
有吃的吗
Got anything to eat?
好吃吗
Enjoying yourself?
我更喜欢鸡肉
I prefer chicken.
你应该加入我们  你对我们有用
You ought to join us. We could use you.
我试过  不适合我
I tried joining. Didn't work out for me.
克里冈  我们在这儿是有缘由的
Clegane, we're here for a reason.
光之王让贝里不死  也是有缘由的
The Lord of Light is keeping Beric alive for a reason.
一个醉醺醺的无能僧侣
He gave a failed, drunk priest
获得起死回生的神力  也是有缘由的
the power to bring him back for a reason.
我们的命运属于某种崇高的事物
We are part of something larger than ourselves.
世上那么多可怜虫  都是因为
Lots of horrible shit in this world gets done
某种崇高的事物而完蛋的
for something larger than ourselves.
北方已有冷风吹起
Cold winds are rising in the North.
你们打算去阻止吗
And you're going to go stop them?
我们需要好手帮忙
We need good men to help us.
上次见到我  你想处决我
Last time you saw me, you wanted to execute me.
没错
True enough.
然而光之王赐你力量击败我
But the Lord of Light gave you the power to defeat me.
为什么
Why?
我打败你  因为我比你强  贝里
I beat you because I'm better than you, Beric.
我当时可比你强
I was better than you
后来你开始哭哭啼啼地喊着真主
before you started yammering on about the Lord
我现在也比你强
and I'm better than you now.
是啊  没准你说得对
Aye, you're probably right.
你是战士
You're a fighter.
生来就是
You were born a fighter.
而你离开了战场
You walked away from the fight.
又是为什么
How did that go?
无论好坏  不分长幼
Good and bad, young and old,
我们的对手会把他们一并消灭
the things we're fighting will destroy them all alike.
你救下的人会远比你伤害过的多  克里冈
You can still help a lot more than you've harmed, Clegane.
对你来说不算太晚
It's not too late for you.
克连恩夫人
Lady Crane?
你要是完成任务  她就不会死得这么痛苦
If you'd have done your job, she would have died painlessly.
结果...
Instead...
有人承诺千面之神一个名字
The Many-Faced God was promised a name.
千面之神就必须得到
He must always receive what is his.
你改变不了
You can't change that.
我改变不了
I can't change that.
谁都改变不了
No one can.
现在又有一个名字给了千面之神
And now he's been promised another name.
-嘿  -闪开
- Hey! - Get out!
我的篮子
My basket!
很快就结束了
It will all be over soon.
跪着还是站着
On your knees or on your feet?
我们又不是没有对练过
Haven't we been through this already?
那个也帮不了你
That won't help you.
你叫她杀我
You told her to kill me.
是的
Yes.
但你还在这里
But here you are.
她在那里
And there she is.
女孩终于成了无名之辈
Finally a girl is no one.
女孩是临冬城的艾莉亚·史塔克
A girl is Arya Stark of Winterfell
我要回家了
and I'm going home.
■
人人影视字幕组推荐
扫一扫关注AppSo
让你的手机好用到哭
■